Calum Woodward

Systems Developer & Certified Scrum Master

+44 (0)7459 101 943 cwdevuk@gmail.com <u>cwoodwarduk.github.io</u> | <u>github.com/cwoodwarduk</u>

I am a constantly-evolving systems developer, a voracious learner, and a certified Agile Scrum Master with a strong understanding of programming fundamentals, a knack for learning and understanding the structure of languages - human or computer.

In my current role, I develop cloud applications and maintain infrastructure for a suite of energy efficiency IoT devices for commercial sites. We use a LAMP stack on AWS, using Terraform for infrastructure configuration. From my previous role I have experience with microservices architecture, to deliver features and maintenance of a CMS platform and associated websites. I also am experienced working in an Agile (Scrum) environment - check out my portfolio to see some of my personal and team projects: cwoodwarduk.github.io

In my free time I like to engage in self-development and have learned Python, React and Java, as well as working on algorithms. I also enjoy learning languages (Korean being my second language), cycling outrageous distances for coffee and cake, making Korean rice wine, and telling dad jokes.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Best.Energy

NOV 2020 - PRESENT

I am responsible for feature builds and maintenance of a cloud IoT platform including API and infrastructure. We utilise a LAMP stack with Laravel and JavaScript to enhance the user experience on the front end, functional PHP on a legacy API, and deployment via DeployHQ on AWS using Terraform for configuration. Our IoT data is handled as binary packages in lieu of a shift to a time-series database. Features I have built include a new cloud admin platform, using both our own API and third-party APIs, as well as contributing to the current migration of our services to AWS and the setup of an MQTT broker including Haproxy servers for load balancing.

Systems Developer - Mosaic Digital Consultants

JAN 2020 - AUG 2020

I was responsible for a CMS platform in PHP (Codelgniter) and its associated websites for Virgin Care and BaNES Council, as well as maintenance of the microservice API that ran it. Features I built include a tool for clients to edit their own website content by altering the websites to allow for dynamic population of every webpage and component, using JavaScript. I also maintained a CMS for schools, contributing features such as a group relationship data visualisation tool. This involved building a node tree search in Laravel.

Language Teacher - various

JUN 2012 - JUN 2019

From 2012 to 2019 I taught English as a foreign language. Six of those years were in South Korea. During this time I taught in large corporations including resident tutor at SK Hynix, state schools, and specialised language schools; and picked up the Korean language.

PROJECTS

CMS and associated websites / ROVa platform for Virgin Care + BaNES Council https://wellbeingcollegebanes.co.uk // <a href="htt

Working on a legacy codebase, I was responsible for the building of new features, bug fixes and other maintenance for both the ROVa CMS, and its associated websites, that run the volunteering services of the BaNES and West Wiltshire regions. The platform was built in PHP (Codelgniter/Laravel), JavaScript (vanilla and JQuery), MySQL, on AWS, with a microservices API.

Ecommerce Website / Ethivore

https://github.com/cwoodwarduk/ethivore_ecommerce

A personal project to develop my knowledge of JavaScript frameworks, I have built and am continuing to build an ecommerce website in a full JS stack using React + Redux for the front end, Express and Node for the RESTful backend, Mongoose for ODM and MongoDB for the database. The project had also been linked up to an AWS S3 bucket for storing images using Multer.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Programming Course - Mayden Academy

AUG - DEC 2019

A four-month intensive course covering HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and databases (MySQL and MongoDB). Frameworks included Slim, Node.js, Express and React. Covered coding principles such as Object-Oriented Programming, REST APIs, SOLID and DRY; as well as best practice such as version control with Git, code review standards, Agile workflow, design patterns and antipatterns, testing using PHPUnit, and using continuous integration servers such as CircleCl.

Certified Scrum Master (CSM) - Scrum Alliance

AUG 2019

Training from Agilify, with certification issued by the Scrum Alliance.

PGCE (Post-Compulsory Education) - Cardiff University

SEP 2010 - JUN 2012

Graduated with a 1st for this teaching certification. Taught courses in archaeology at Cardiff University and Essential Skills Wales training to three centres in the greater Cardiff area.

BA (Hons) Archaeology - University of Wales

SEP 2007 - JUN 2010

Graduated with a 2:1, also having spent a year as Entertainments Manager of the student union, Social Secretary of the men's field hockey team, and participated in an overseas research project in Cyprus. I studied modules in web design in my first year.